We are officially preparing for the ordain beginning today.
你們從今天開始 就要正式為得度做準備了
Are you all ready?
你們做好覺悟了嗎
Yes!
是的
Show that annoying monk a bit of attitude.
我們一定要給那個臭和尚 一點顏色看看
Then let me ask you all.
那我來問問你們
What colors are your underwear now?
你們現在的內褲是什麼顏色的
White,
是白色嗎
or other colors?
還是其他顏色的
Kiki,
嬉嬉姐
we don't have much time, please take it seriously.
我們時間不多了 請妳認真一點…
I'm quite serious!
我是超級認真的
The so-called practice involves
所謂修行
returning the mind and body to a state of pure innocence.
就是為了讓身心重回純潔無瑕的狀態
Even a piece of underwear has to meet a clear rule:
即便是一件內衣褲 也都有明確的規範
it has to be white and plain.
你們必須穿簡樸的白色才行
I don't have white.
我沒有白色的
And I like to wear boxers.
而且我都穿四角褲
I've washed mine.
我的拿去洗了
I only have red and black!
我只有紅色和黑色的
Red and black?
紅色和黑色…
Eh, why are you all so surprised?
咦 你們為什麼這麼驚訝啊
Don't you all have white underwear?
你們都沒有白色的內衣褲嗎
Then there's no choice.
那沒辦法了
No underwear
我要你們今天
for practice today, everyone.
都不穿內衣褲進行修行
WORLDLY DESIRES
(世俗雜念)
(TenPuru -No one can live on loneliness-)
《妙廟美少女》
(Episode 7: What color is your underwear?)
(第七集 你的內褲是什麼顏色？)
This is so unsettling.
這是何等的不安
Such a shameful thing.
這麼羞恥的事情
Yuzuki, you don't mind at all?
結月妳完全不在意嗎
W-Well…Although it is somewhat embarrassing,
嗯 嗯…雖然有些羞恥
it is simply part of the practice.
但把這個當做修行的話 也就不算什麼了
Miss Kiki.
嬉嬉小姐
Thank you.
謝謝妳我恨妳
You have a very interesting way of speaking.
你這說話方式真有意思
First is Zazen.
首先是坐禪
Assume the correct posture.
姿勢要端正
Settle your mind.
並讓精神平靜下來
No matter what evil thoughts arise,
不管起了什麼邪念
you must not succumb to it.
你們都絕不能屈服於它
Those who are not taking this seriously
誰不認真坐禪
I am so grateful.
不勝感激
This is the practice
這就是
I am interested in.
我所追求的修行
Lips slightly closed, eyes slightly open,
雙唇輕閉雙目微張
and slowly inhale through the nose.
然後用鼻子慢慢地呼吸
This is Zazen.
這就是坐禪
Ignoring distracting thoughts
完全無視世俗雜念
and focusing solely on the air
只是感受著空氣
and the passage of time.
任憑時間流淌
This is what they call purifying the mind, right?
這就是所謂的淨化心靈吧
What's wrong with you, Akagami?
你怎麼了 赤神
Sit up.
給我坐起來
Next is the copying of a sutra.
接下來是抄寫經書
NET PROFIT Copy each word carefully.
每一個字
That was so out of character.
我剛剛是何等的失態
There won't be any problems this time.
不過這次我應該就沒問題了吧
Oh. Akagami, you write pretty well.
哦…你寫得不錯嘛 赤神
I used to work in a calligraphy classroom.
其實我以前有在書法教室打過工
Having good handwriting is an advantage for the abbot, huh.
字寫得好看 對於住持來說是個優勢哦
You should go teach Yuzuki to write.
你去教教結月怎麼寫吧
I will leave for a minute.
我稍微離開一下
Miss Yuzuki,
結月小姐
the way you hold the pen…
妳拿筆的姿勢
So erotic!
好色情
So erotic?
很色情嗎
I'm sorry!
對不起
Your thumb should be here.
首先是妳的大拇指…
Oh my. Here's the tissue.
哎呀真是的 來 這是面紙
BETWEEN THE LEGS, NO UNDERWEAR
(胯下 沒穿內褲)
Let me wipe it for you.
我幫你擦一擦吧
Miss Mia?
米亞小姐
It's okay.
沒關係的
Miss Mia, stop! Don't continue!
米亞小姐 住手 再這樣下去…
Why are you only hitting me?
妳為什麼只打我
Um…
那個…
Today, I've been lagging behind the whole day.
我們今天老是扯大家後腿
How should we apologize?
我們應該怎麼表達歉意才好呢
It's okay, it's okay.
沒事啦沒事啦
Uh... Well.
啊…那個
You don't have to worry about me.
你們不用勉強自己配合我
You two continue shopping…
只要慢慢來就…
No, no! It's fine!
不不 我們完全沒問題
I bought white underwear!
我們買到白色內褲了
And a bra too!
我也買胸罩了
I'm all prepared now.
這樣就準備妥當了
Right, Akagami.
對呀赤神
These two seem to get along quite well.
這兩個人還挺像的呢
KIDNEY BEAN Let's rest well today
那麼 為了明天能夠繼續努力
and work hard tomorrow.
我們今天就好好休息吧
Understood.
收到
We're back.
我們回來了
You three will be sleeping here starting today.
從今天開始 你們三個必須睡在這裡
When participating in the practice,
修行的時候
everyone sleeps on a single tatami mat.
每個人都只能睡一張榻榻米
Learning to accept this now is harmless.
你們趁現在先習慣 是不會吃虧的
How can I sleep here?
這樣誰睡得著啊
And it's just the mattress.
而且只有床墊而已
Men and women usually sleep separately, right, Kiki?
一般都是男女分開睡的吧 嬉嬉姐
Kiki.
嬉嬉姐
That's the way! That's how you can sleep!
就是這樣 這樣就能睡覺了
That's right!
沒錯
You're impressive, Akagami!
真不愧是赤神呢
What are you up to?
你這是什麼意思
There's no need to be so hasty.
沒有必要這麼著急
Let her ordain.
讓她得度吧…
There will be an internal meeting
三個月後
about this temple three months later.
會在這所寺廟舉行法類會議
This is a decision from above.
這是上面的決定
Wha--
什…
Just please don't
請妳不要
nullify my engagement.
讓我的婚約變成無意義了
Geez.
真是的
We'll just have to beat a dead horse?
我也只能死馬當活馬醫了嗎
I didn't sleep for a second.
結果我們都沒能睡著…
Today we're going to do a kind of
今天我們要來做一種
It's also a reward for your previous efforts.
順便獎勵一下努力至今的你們
A reward?
什麼獎勵
SAUNA, PRIVATE SESSIONS ARE AVAILABLE, POST-CEREMONY CELEBRATION Why a sauna?
為什麼是三溫暖
And why is it mixed bathing?
而且還是男女混浴
Aren't you happy?
你不高興嗎
That's precisely the problem.
就是因為高興所以才困擾啊
This is the only way.
這只是一點激烈手段罷了
Face your own distracting thoughts
你們要各自面對自己的雜念
while also increasing your endurance for the opposite sex.
順便也強化一下自己對於異性的耐性
This is also for…
所以你們需要...
Um…how should I put it?
嗯…怎麼說呢…
-Enjoy yourselves. -Enjoy what?
你們好好體驗吧
Cheer up, Akagami.
加油吧 赤神
If this level of difficulty is unbearable,
這種程度就叫苦連天的話
you will not be able to ordain in three months.
我們肯定沒辦法在三個月內得度的
Yes, Yuzu--
是啊 結月小…
I'm okay.
我沒事的
I am too.
我也是
My mind is full of distracting thoughts!
我的腦子裡全是雜念
Can I really suppress these distracting thoughts?
我真的能克制住這些雜念嗎
I-It's a bit crowded.
有…有點擠呢
S-Sorry.
抱…抱歉
Akagami?
赤神
I'm sorry, Miss Mia!
對不起 米亞小姐
I'm okay, Akagami.
我沒事的 赤神
But…
但是…
I hope you can turn off the light before doing it.
我希望你能關了燈再做
That doesn't look okay at all!
這樣怎麼可能沒事啊
Miss Mia, this won't do.
米亞小姐 這樣不行啊
Indeed.
的確…
We can't keep holding Miss Yuzuki back.
我們不能再扯結月小姐的後腿了
Let's have a meeting.
我們來開個討論會吧
Let's discuss our progress in practice.
各自說說修行的成果
Y-Yeah.
對 對呀
Yesterday, we copied a sutra and did Zazen.
昨天的修行是抄寫經書和坐禪
Sleeping together
還有
is also regarded as practice.
三個人一起睡覺應該也算修行吧
Oh, speaking of which,
啊 說到這個
while sleeping last night, I noticed something.
昨天睡覺的時候 我發現了一件事…
What?
什麼事
I like Adam's apples.
原來我有戀喉結癖
Akagami's Adam's apple is bulging.
赤神的喉結鼓鼓的
It's so charming.
好迷人呀
This has nothing to do with enlightenment at all!
這和開悟一點關係都沒有
Oh my, I'm talking about such things again.
真是的 我怎麼又這樣了
A-Akagami, how about you?
赤 赤神 那你修行得怎麼樣呢
M-Me…
我…我嘛
Last night, I stayed firm
昨天晚上
all night!
堅挺了一整晚
You're so manly, Akagami!
你好有男人味呀 赤神
What am I saying?
我到底在說什麼啊
Miss Yuzuki's face is all red.
結月小姐的臉都紅起來了
Why? Distracting thoughts keep popping up!
為什麼 雜念總是源源不絕地冒出來
If this continues, Miss Yuzuki will dislike me,
再這樣下去 我會被結月小姐給討厭
and my qualification to ordain will be revoked.
最終會被取消得度的資格的
I see.
原來是這樣…
Miss Kiki's purpose is now clear to me.
我明白了 嬉嬉小姐的目的…
She wants us to experience
她是想讓我們體驗一下
the demonic realm.
什麼是魔境啊
Demonic realm?
魔境…
Is Miss Yuzuki fainting from the heat?
結月小姐因為熱氣而胡言亂語了嗎
I-It's all because of the trouble I caused.
都…都是因為我惹出的麻煩
I'm okay!
我沒事
The demonic realm is a term in Buddhism.
魔境是佛教用語
In both heaven and earth, only I am supreme!
天上天下唯我獨尊
Speaking of which, I'm so hungry.
話說我好餓啊
The so-called demonic realm
所謂魔境
is about entering a state of extreme euphoria
就是指通過嚴酷的修行
by rigorously visualizing the troubles and distracting thoughts
將自己內心深處 沉眠的煩惱與雜念具象化
that are deep asleep in your heart.
從而進入一種極度興奮的狀態
You will no longer
只要能克服這個
be swayed by distracting thoughts as long as you can overcome this.
我們就不會再被雜念所影響了
This was the experience
什麼 嬉嬉小姐叫我們來體驗
Miss Kiki was referring to?
原來是這麼回事啊
Yeah, it should be.
嗯…應該吧
Next, it's Miss Yuzuki's turn.
那接下來就輪到結月小姐了
Come on, Miss Yuzuki.
來吧 結月小姐也來暢談
Let's talk about explicit sexual vocabulary.
赤裸裸的色情詞彙吧
Don't make it sound like we're telling dirty jokes.
妳不要說得我們好像 在講色情話題一樣啊
Come on!
來吧 來吧
Well… I…
那個…我…
I can't say it aloud,
說不出口…
but I am fascinated by Akagami's nakedness
我很在意赤神的裸體…
or a particular part of his body.
或者說是他身體的一部分的事情
I can't stop thinking about the naked body
之前在愛情旅館看到的裸體什麼的
I saw in a love hotel.
一直都在我腦海裡揮之不去
Not to mention,
更不用說
I also thought about the possible events that might happen afterwards.
我還想了一下 後續可能發生的事情什麼的
I can't say it out loud.
我說不出口
And…
而且…
I don't seem to have
我好像沒有吧
any distracting thoughts.
雜念
Really?
真的嗎
Miss Yuzuki has overcome the demonic realm
結月小姐已經克服了魔境
and entered the state of selflessness.
進入無我的境界了
As expected of Yuzuki!
真不愧是結月小姐
Um… Yeah…
嗯…嗯…
The practice ended smoothly.
修行順利結束了呢
Let's report to Kiki.
我們去向嬉嬉姐報告吧
Yeah, I can't say it out loud.
是的…我說不出口…
After all, this is
畢竟這是
a personal matter unrelated to practice.
與修行無關的我的個人問題
When I see how well they get along,
看到他們兩個這麼要好
it makes my heart hurt.
我的內心就很焦躁什麼的
I can't say it out loud.
我都說不出口
Anyway, this is special practice.
總之 這就是特別修行了
It seems to have an effect.
看起來修行是有成效的嘛
Yes!
是
I clearly felt my own distracting thoughts.
我清晰地認知到了自己的雜念
Well, that's the best.
嗯 那就再好不過了
Distracting thoughts will persist toward enlightenment.
想要開悟 就必然會殘留雜念
That is why you must confront distracting thoughts.
正因如此才不能逃避 而且還要去面對雜念
I see.
原來如此…
If someone claims to
如果今天
have no distracting thoughts,
有人說自己沒有雜念的話
he or she must be a sulky pervert.
那他肯定是個最悶騷的色狼了
I'm not perverted at all.
我一點都不色啦
A COMPASSIONATE PERSON FINDS JOY IN HELPING OTHERS
(仁者樂山)
You guys have become very proficient.
看來你們進步很大嘛
Thank you for the compliment.
謝謝誇獎
Let's give you the afternoon off.
我今天下午就給你們放個假吧
Why, Kiki?
為什麼啊 嬉嬉姐
That's right.
沒錯
The practice has just begun!
修行才正要開始而已耶
Calm down.
你們先冷靜點
You will only harm your body if you push yourself so hard.
你們這麼急躁地勉強自己 也只會讓身體受傷罷了
But…
但是…
Not seeking fame and fortune.
名利共休
You understand, don't you, Yuzuki?
妳知道這句話吧 結月
Not seeking?
名…
Not seeking fame and fortune entails
名利共休是
not considering gains and losses
不考慮利益與得失
and instead facing one's surroundings and oneself calmly.
靜心去面對周遭和自我的意思
This is most likely the third point of the first experience of enlightenment.
這算是首次開悟心得的第三點吧
In short, rest is also part of the practice.
總之就是休息也是修行的一環
Then I'm going to go play with Kagura. It is been a long time!
那我要久違地去找神樂出去玩啦
How could it be?
怎麼會…
There's a day off today.
這一天竟然會放假
What's wrong, Akagami?
怎麼了 赤神
Today is December 24th.
今天是12月24日
It's also Christmas.
也就是聖誕節
Huh? Akagami, do you dislike Christmas?
咦 你討厭聖誕節嗎
Every Christmas,
每年一到聖誕節
my father would spend every waking moment planning how to deal with his mistress.
老爹就會以分鐘為單位 想方設法地對付他的情人
Every time this happened,
每到這時候
my house would turn into a bloody battlefield.
我家就會掀起一場血雨腥風
Christmas is so scary.
聖誕節好可怕
Christmas is so sad.
聖誕節好淒慘
Um…
那個…
In that case, would you like
這樣的話…
to go out with me? Just the two of us.
你要不要和我出去呢 就我們兩個
There will be a Christmas party tomorrow.
畢竟明天大家會舉辦聖誕派對嘛
Huh? At the temple?
咦 在寺廟裡嗎
Yes, and also,
嗯 而且呢
there is a gift exchange session.
我們還有禮物交換環節呢
Let's choose gifts together.
我們就一起挑禮物吧
Okay, I got it.
好 好 的 我 明白了
What's wrong, Akagami?
你怎麼了 赤神
24TH DECEMBER, CHRISTMAS EVE It's just too subtle for two people
聖誕夜兩人結伴外出
to go out in pairs on Christmas Eve!
這實在是太意味深了
Especially with Miss Yuzuki!
而且對象還是結月小姐
Christmas songs and decorations everywhere.
聖誕歌和隨處可見的燈飾
There is a breezy, carefree vibe all along the street.
整條街道都縈繞著輕飄飄的氛圍
Damn it,
可惡
so this is Christmas Eve!
這就是聖誕夜
I will never become one of them.
我絕不會迎合它的
Let's go, Akagami.
我們走吧 赤神
Okay!
好
Over here.
這邊哦
What about this one?
這個怎麼樣
So cute.
好可愛
I was too carried away!
我太得意忘形了
Is this the magic of Christmas Eve?
這就是聖誕夜的魔力嗎
My practice is far from enough.
我的修行還遠遠不夠
Have you decided what gift to buy?
你決定好買什麼禮物了嗎
Oh…not yet…
啊…還沒…
I'm struggling with what gift to buy.
我還在糾結要買什麼禮物
You do not need to overthink it.
你不用想的那麼複雜啦
Really?
真的嗎
Simply choose the present
你只要帶著平日裡對大家的感激
that best expresses your gratitude to them.
挑選自己想送的禮物就好啦
I see.
原來如此
By the way, there's a store I want to recommend to you.
對了 我有一家店要推薦給你哦
BUDDHIST SUPPLY STORE
(佛具店)
-Is this a Buddhist supply store? -Yes.
-這是佛具店嗎 -是呀
This store is opened by my senior.
這家店是我的學姐開的
The products available here
這裡的商品
are essentially temple necessities.
對於寺廟來說基本上都是日用品
It should be easier to choose, right?
我想說這樣應該會比較好挑吧
Oh… I see.
哦哦…原來如此
Prayer beads, huh?
佛珠嗎…
Are you buying this?
你要買這個嗎
No, I was just thinking I don't have one yet.
不是 我只是在想我剛好沒有呢
I only have a simple one.
我也只有一個略式的呢
Simple?
略式…
There are simple and formal prayer beads.
佛珠有分略式和本式哦
For the ordaining ceremony or other major events,
像是得度主儀式或者其他重要場合
you have to use formal prayer beads.
就要使用本式的佛珠
But they are quite expensive.
不過那個還挺貴的
I could only borrow from Kiki or my parents during the ordaining ceremony.
所以在得度儀式上 我也只能 借嬉嬉姐或者我父母的來用了
Is that so?
原來是這樣啊
I need to get my own prayer beads
我想要快點獨當一面
and stand on my own two feet soon.
買一串自己的佛珠
Action speaks louder than words, buy it now.
心動不如行動 現在就買吧
-Mary. -Welcome, Yuzuki.
-真梨學姊 -歡迎光臨 小結
Long time no see. This is Akagami.
好久不見 這位是赤神
Nice to meet you.
初次見面
This is my senior, Mary.
這是我的學姊真梨
Hello.
你好你好
If you're looking for prayer beads, I have some recommendations.
如果你們在找佛珠的話 我這裡有推薦的哦
Love prayer beads for couples.
男女成對的恩愛佛珠
Huh? There's such a thing?
咦 還有這種的嗎
Yes.
有哦有哦
After all, in a Buddhist wedding,
畢竟佛教的婚禮上
what's exchanged are not rings but prayer beads.
交換的不是戒指而是佛珠哦
Exchange prayer beads?
交換佛珠嗎
This is quite obscure knowledge.
這個知識還挺冷門的呢
Others,
其他還有…
such as the one aimed at couples
適合情侶的這種
and the one for husband and wife to have children and good fortune.
適合夫妻的 多子多孫的…
Why do you keep recommending these to me?
妳為什麼一直在給我們 介紹這一類的啊
Aren't you two a couple?
你們不是情侶嗎
Couple?
情侶…
No, I've already said he's not.
不是 我都說了他不是了…
Really?
是嗎
You guys came here together on Christmas Eve,
畢竟你們兩個是在聖誕夜來的嘛
I thought you're definitely on a date.
我還以為你們肯定是在約會呢
Uh? Did she just realize it now?
呃 難道說 她現在才注意到嗎
Um… we're really not in that kind of relationship.
那個…我們真的不是那種關係
Really?
真的嗎
Really no chance?
真的沒戲嗎
Uh, well… I guess so…
呃 算是吧…
But Yuzuki's face is red, so it looks like there is a chance.
但是小結滿臉通紅 你們看上去相當有戲啊
Don't look at me, Akagami.
你別看我 赤神
I see that Yuzuki is quite exciting.
因為小結妳看起來很來勁啊
Her usual attire is more casual,
妳平時的穿著會更隨意一些
but she did put on makeup today, which is unusual.
妳今天甚至非常難得地化了妝
And it seems she's gained a bit of weight.
而且妳好像還有點發福…
Mary, I'll take this one!
真梨學姊 這個我要了
Okay, thank you for your patronage.
好 多謝惠顧
It's not what you think!
我們真的不是那種關係啦
PRAYER BEAD HANDCRAFTING EXPERIENCE STARTING FROM 1000 YEN, SUITABLE FOR AGES 5 AND ABOVE.
(佛珠手工製作體驗 1000日元起 限五歲以上體驗)
-Alright. -Geez.
-好啦好啦… -真是的
Akagami, have you picked out a gift?
赤神 你挑好禮物了嗎
Yes. Thanks to you.
是啊 這都多虧了妳
That's great.
那就好
Could it be…
該不會
Miss Yuzuki is trying to cheer me up?
結月小姐是想讓我打起精神吧
Miss Yuzuki.
結月小姐…
I'm looking forward to tomorrow.
我好期待明天呀
Me too, Akagami.
就是說呀 赤神
It's Christmas again, huh?
今年也到聖誕節了嗎
The year went by so fast.
這一年過得好快
Speaking of which, isn't it a bit too chaotic right now?
話說 我們最近 是不是有點忙過頭了呀
Indeed, the changes are quite significant.
就是說呀 變化十分顯著
I have also reached adulthood.
我也成為了一個 名符其實的成年女性
The most noticeable change has to be Mia.
要說變化最明顯的 應該就是米亞了吧
It must be the result of her practice.
那應該是修行的成果所致吧
You have turned into a slutty person.
妳變色情了…
What did you say?
你們說啥
At first, you had a little bit of a pure vibe,
(絕不露出自己的肌膚) 妳一開始是有點潔身自好的那種感覺
NEVER REVEAL SKIN but now there is no sign of it.
(不潔身自好的人應當以死謝罪) 現在卻連影子都看不到了
Your outfit has also changed.
穿著打扮也變了
Your clothes now highlight your curves more.
現在更加強調身體的曲線了
I don't have that kind of thought!
我才沒有這種想法
Sorry.
抱歉抱歉
This kind of attire suits you, and it's not for any lewd reasons.
這樣的打扮很適合妳 而且妳這樣穿 也不是因為什麼奇怪的理由吧
I just wanted Akagami to stare at my chest!
我只是想讓赤神盯著我的胸部看而已
This reason is outrageously lewd!
這理由簡直下流得離譜
I'm not.
我才沒有
Sis Tsukuyo has also become lewd.
月夜姐姐也變下流了
What are you saying?
妳說什麼呢
Sis Yuzuki is as introverted as ever.
結月姐姐一如既往的悶騷
Alright.
好了好了…
In any case,
總之就是
we've all changed because of him.
我們大家都因他而改變了呢
Before, the four of us
以前我們四個人
even discussed how to drive Akagami out.
還曾經一起商量過 要怎麼把赤神給趕出去呢
There was such a thing.
就是說呀
The biggest change has to be
最大的變化肯定是
the fact that Akagami came to the temple.
赤神哥哥來到寺廟裡這件事
No one would think of
趕他出去這種事
driving him out now.
現在已經不會有人再這麼想了呢
He really is an interesting person.
他真是個有趣的人啊
Akagami.
赤神
But he's also really a nuisance.
但他也真的很礙事
Let's drive him out.
我來把他驅逐出去吧
(Next Episode: Encountering a Turtle Symbolizes Good Fortune) Question,
(下集 看到烏龜代表著好運) 提問
what's that swaying
在身體中間
in the middle of your body?
(下集 看到烏龜代表著好運) 搖搖晃晃的那個是什麼
The one that sometimes gets bigger and sometimes smaller, right?
是時而變大時而變小的那個 對吧
Wait-- Mia?
(下集 看到烏龜代表著好運) 等一…米亞
The one that makes you an adult when you do it alone, right?
一個人弄的話